Guide to the Jack Metcalf Papers 1973-2001
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
- Congressional Career, 1984-2001; 1995-2000; Series II
  - Washington D.C. Office files, 1984-2001; (bulk 1995-2000); Subseries 1
    - Legislative Issues, 1984-2001
      - Resources, 1992-2000; (bulk 1995-2000)
        - Hanford Trip, 1997 (Box-folder 18/37)
        - Heritage Areas (HR 1280), 1996 (Box-folder 18/38)
        - High Production Volume Chemical Testing – EPA Program, 1999 (Box-folder 18/39)
        - I-90 Land Exchange, 1998 (Box-folder 18/40)
        - Illegal Aliens (Forest and Timber industry), 1998 (Box-folder 18/41)
        - Interior Columbia Basin Impact Statements, circa 1999 (Box-folder 18/42)
        - John Wayne Trail though Yakima Training Center, 1998 (Box-folder 18/43)
        - King County Washington – Energy and Water requests, 2000 (Box-folder 18/44)
        - Lake Clark National Park (HR 2560), circa 1996 (Box-folder 18/45)
        - Land and Water Conservation Fund FY2000 requests, 1999 (Box-folder 18/46)
        - Land and Water Conservation Fund / Conservation and Reinvestment Act, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 18/47)
        - League of Conservation Voters, 1997 (Box-folder 19/1)
        - Legislative “Sign-ons”, 1998 (Box-folder 19/2)
        - Lewis and Clark Trail, 1997 (Box-folder 19/3)
        - Maxwelton Creek, 1999 (Box-folder 19/4)
        - Mining, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 19/5)
        - Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest, circa 1996 (Box-folder 19/6)
        - Mount St. Helens Land Exchange, 1997 (Box-folder 19/7)
        - Mountain Loop Scenic Byway, undated (Box-folder 19/8)
        - Mukilteo Tank Farm, 2000 (Box-folder 19/9)
        - National Institute for the Environment (H.R. 2914), 1998 (Box-folder 19/10)
        - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 19/11)
        - National Park / Outdoor activities reform, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 19/12)
        - National Parks Concession Reform, 1995 (Box-folder 19/13)
        - National Parks reform legislation, 1996; 1998 (Box-folder 19/14 - 19/15)
        - National Wildlife Refuge legislation, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 19/16)
        - Northwest Marine Straits Sanctuary, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 19/17 - 19/18)
        - Nuclear Waste, 1997 (Box-folder 19/19)
        - Oeser Company Superfund, 1997 (Box-folder 19/20)
        - Oil Heat, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 19/21)
        - Organic Foods – Draft Legislation, 1998 (Box-folder 19/22)
        - Organic Foods – general information, 1999 (Box-folder 19/23)
        - Organic Foods - The Law and Current Regulations, 1997 (Box-folder 19/24)
        - Organic Foods - Letters and Responses, 1998 (Box-folder 19/25)
        - Organic Foods – Press Clippings, 1998 (Box-folder 19/26)
        - Organic Foods - Speeches and Press Releases, 1998 (Box-folder 19/27)
        - Organic Foods – Standards and Labeling, 1998 (Box-folder 19/28)
        - Pacific Crest Trail, 1999 (Box-folder 19/29)
        - Pacific Northwest Trail Association – Swift Creek Trail, 1999 (Box-folder 19/30)
        - Park Outfitters and Guides legislation, circa 1996 (Box-folder 19/31)
        - Pellet Fuels, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 19/32)
        - Propane – EPA Risk Management rules, 1999 (Box-folder 19/33)
        - Property Rights and Land Protection, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 19/34)
        - Puget Sound Ecosystem Restoration Initiative, 2000 (Box-folder 19/35)
        - Refridgerants – EPA Proposals, 1998 (Box-folder 19/36)
        - Reiter Pond Hatchery, 1999 (Box-folder 19/37)
        - Rural Water, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 19/38)
        - Sector Facility Indexing Project (EPA), 1997 (Box-folder 19/39)
        - Skagit Plant Material Center (Bow, WA), 1997 (Box-folder 19/40)
        - Skagit Watershed Council, 1997 (Box-folder 19/41)
        - Skagit Wild and Scenic River Corridor, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 19/42)
        - Snake River Salmon, 1997 (Box-folder 19/43)
        - Sportsman’s Caucus, 1997 (Box-folder 19/44)
        - Sugar Subsidies / Everglades Restoration, 1998 (Box-folder 19/45)
        - Superfund - natural resource damages, 1997 (Box-folder 19/46)
        - Superfund – nuclear waste, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 19/47)
        - Superfund reform legislation, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 19/48)
        - Superfund sites, 1998 (Box-folder 19/49)
        - Thunder Creek Mines (North Cascades National Park), 2000 (Box-folder 19/50)
        - Tulalip Landfill Superfund, 1997 (Box-folder 19/51)
        - Utah Public Land Management (HR 1745), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 19/52)
        - Washington Conservation Districts, 1997 (Box-folder 19/53)
        - Washington Tribes – zoning, fire and water resources, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 19/54)
        - Water Quality, 1997 (Box-folder 19/55)
        - Western Caucus, 1998 (Box-folder 19/56)
        - World Heritage Areas, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 19/57)
      - Science and Telecommunications, 1996-2000
        Science and Telecommunications files include materials pertaining to the anti-trust case against Microsoft between 1997 and 1999.
        - Bonneville Power Administration Fiber Network, 1999 (Box-folder 20/1)
        - Cell Tower Sitings (Lopez Island WA), 1999 (Box-folder 20/2)
        - Cell Towers (Friday Harbor), 1996 (Box-folder 20/3)
        - Committee on Science – Membership and Rules, 1999 (Box-folder 20/4)
        - Communications Decency Act, 1998 (Box-folder 20/5)
        - Copyright Law – Sensenbrenner Amendment, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 20/6)
        - “E-rate” program, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 20/7)
        - High Performance Computers, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 20/8)
        - Home Page Tax, 1999 (Box-folder 20/9)
        - Incumbent Local Exhange Carrier complaints, 1999 (Box-folder 20/10)
        - Internet Tax (H.R. 4105), 1998 (Box-folder 20/11)
        - Microradio (low power FM / Radio Broadcasting Preservation Act), 1999-2000 (Box-folder 20/12 - 20/13)
        - Microsoft Anti-Trust Case, 1999 (Box-folder 20/14)
        - Microsoft Decree Amendments (Windows 95 Operating System), 1997-1998 (Box-folder 20/15 - 20/16)
        - Public TV Authorization (Corporation for Public Broadcasting Act), 1999 (Box-folder 20/17)
        - Reciprocal Compensation (Dial-up Internet Access), 1999 (Box-folder 20/18)
        - Regional Bell Companies – Internet Entry, 1999 (Box-folder 20/19)
        - Satellite Copyright, Competition and Consumer Protection Act (H.R. 1554), 1999 (Box-folder 20/20)
        - Satellite Home Viewer Act, 1999 (Box-folder 20/21)
        - Telecommunications Act of 1996, 1999 (Box-folder 20/22)
        - Voice Stream / Deutsche Telekom merger, 2000 (Box-folder 20/23)
        - Washington Software Alliance Roundtable, 1999 December 2 (Box-folder 20/24)
      - Timber Files, 1995-2000
        - Below-Cost Timber Sales, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 20/25 - 20/26)
        - Clinton Administration Roadless Area Policy, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 20/27 - 20/28)
        - County Timber Payments (H.R. 2389), 1999 (Box-folder 20/29)
        - Forest Products Tariff initiative, 1997 (Box-folder 20/30)
        - Forestry and Timber – general issues file, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 20/31)
        - Forestry Training, circa 1996 (Box-folder 20/32)
        - I-90 Land Exchange, 1997 (Box-folder 20/33)
        - Northwest Woodlands Owners’ Council, 1997 (Box-folder 20/34)
        - Pulp and Paper Industry – EPA Cluster Rules, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 20/35)
        - Salvage Timber, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 20/36)
        - Shi Shi Beach, 1998 (Box-folder 20/37)
        - Timber Exports, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 20/38)
        - Tongass National Forest Timber (Alaska), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 20/39)
        - U.S. – Canada Softwood Agreement, 1997; 1999-2000 (Box-folder 20/40)
        - United States Forest Service – Huckleberry Land Exchange, 1998 (Box-folder 20/41)
        - United States Forest Service – Kennedy/Porter Amendment, 1997 (Box-folder 20/42)
        - United States Forest Service – Trail User Fee, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 20/43)
      - Tribal Issues, 1995-2000
        Tribal Issues files document Metcalf’s role in legislative attempts to limit sovereign immunity for tribes receiving federal funds and also to restrict the process for tribal determination. Materials also include correspondence and funding proposals regarding the Lummi Tribal School and requests for assistance to displaced Lummi Fishers after cancellation of the 1999 sockeye fishing season. Correspondence and permit applications reflect disputes between the Lummi Indian Nation and Sandy Point Improvement Company regarding water and tidelands rights.
        - Acquisition of Indian Trust Land, 1997 (Box-folder 21/1)
        - Appraisals of Certain Leasehold of Restricted Indian Lands, 1997 (Box-folder 21/2)
        - Colorado Ute Tribes – Water Rights, 1999 (Box-folder 21/3)
        - Gaming, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 21/4)
        - Lummi Nation Tribal School, 1998 (Box-folder 21/5)
        - Lummi Nation Tribal School – Construction, 1998 (Box-folder 21/6)
        - Lummi Nation - Water Rights and Utilities, 1995; 1998 (Box-folder 21/7)
        - Lummi Nation – Request for Assistance (Sockeye Fishing Collapse), 1999-2000 (Box-folder 21/8)
        - Lummi Shore Road, 1996 (Box-folder 21/9)
        - Mukilteo Tank Farm, 2000 (Box-folder 21/10)
        - Nooksack Tribe – Federal Funds, 1996 (Box-folder 21/11)
        - Sandy Point Restoration Project Permits, 1998 (Box-folder 21/12)
        - Sandy Point Tidelands, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 21/13)
        - Statements and Articles re: Tribal Issues, circa 1995 (Box-folder 21/14)
        - Swinomish Utility Tax, 1998 (Box-folder 21/15)
        - Tribal Sovereign Immunity – Senate Committee Hearing, September 24, 1996 (Box-folder 21/16)
        - Tribal Sovereignty – Gorton Amendment, 1997 (Box-folder 21/17)
        - Tribal Sovereignty – Metcalf Bill, 1996 (Box-folder 21/18)
        - Tulalip Housing, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 21/19)
      - Water and Shipping, 1996-2000
        Water and Shipping files document Metcalf’s interest in proposals to restore and develop waterways and port access at regional sites (including Bellingham Bay, Stillaguamish River, the Columbia lower basin and the Port of Seattle), and his establishment with U.S. Senator Patty Murray of the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative (1998).
        - Albeni Falls Dam (Bonner ID), 1998 (Box-folder 22/1)
        - Blaine Waste Water Treatment Plant / Lummi Burial Grounds, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 22/2)
        - Clean Water Act reauthorization, 1999 (Box-folder 22/3)
        - Clean Water Act Infrastructure Financing, 1999 (Box-folder 22/4)
        - Coast Guard Authorization Act – Coastal Venture, 1999 (Box-folder 22/5)
        - Coastal Zone Management Act, 2000 (Box-folder 22/6)
        - Columbia River Channel Improvement, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 22/7)
        - Combined Sewer Overflow Control and Partnership Act, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 22/8)
        - Dredging (Oak Harbor), 1997 (Box-folder 22/9)
        - Flood Control – Sacramento, 1998 (Box-folder 22/10)
        - Flood Insurance – Island County, 1998 (Box-folder 22/11)
        - Flood Protection legislation, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 22/12)
        - Ground Water, 1999 (Box-folder 22/13)
        - Ground Water/Private Wells, 1998 (Box-folder 22/14)
        - Harbor Maintenance Funding, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 22/15)
        - Intertanko v Governor of Washington, 2000 (Box-folder 22/16)
        - Low Flow Toilets, 1999 (Box-folder 22/17)
        - Maritime Administration Title XI Ship Loan Guarantee Program, 2000 (Box-folder 22/18)
        - Maritime Administration Title XI Finance (Nichols Brothers Boat Builders), 2000 (Box-folder 22/19)
        - Marshland Dike program (Snohomish County), 1997 (Box-folder 22/20)
        - Mukilteo Tank Farm, 1999 (Box-folder 22/21)
        - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, 1997 (Box-folder 22/22)
        - North American Conservation Wetlands Act, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 22/23)
        - Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 22/24)
        - Oil Spills, 1999 (Box-folder 22/25)
        - Pacific Northwest Waterways, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 22/26)
        - Port of Everett Dry Dock proposals, undated (Box-folder 22/27)
        - Port of Seattle – New Solutions Cargo Control, undated (Box-folder 22/28)
        - Puget Sound Shipping Safety, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 22/29)
        - Sacramento Levees and Folsom Dam, 1998 (Box-folder 22/30)
        - Sail the San Juans/Coast Guard, 1999 (Box-folder 22/31)
        - Stillaguamish Restoration project, 2000 (Box-folder 22/32)
        - Swinomish Marina, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 22/33)
        - Tug Escorts, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 22/34)
        - “Tug of Opportunity” proposals, 1997 (Box-folder 22/35)
        - Tulalip Chinook and Water Studies, 2000 (Box-folder 22/36)
        - Veterans Affairs, Housing and Urban Development Subcommittee funding request, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 22/37)
        - Waste Flow Control, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 22/38)
        - Water Resources Development Act, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 22/39 - 22/41)
        - Water Resources Development Act (Bellingham Bay, Seattle and Stillaguamish), 1998-1999 (Box-folder 22/42)
        - Water Resources Development Act (Howard Hanson Dam), 1999 (Box-folder 22/43)
        - Whidbey Island Waste Water Plant, 1998 (Box-folder 22/44)
      - Whales and Marine Mammals, 1995-2000
        Records include research materials, reports, petitions, correspondence and statements documenting Metcalf’s opposition to the resumption of whaling by the Makah Tribe in Neah Bay, Washington. Researchers should note that Metcalf’s Press and Publicity Files also contain a file of newspaper clippings about the Makah whaling.
        - Family Pet Protection Act (HR 3393), 1996 June-September (Box-folder 23/1)
        - First Assembly of the World Council of Whalers Resolution, 1998 June 11 (Box-folder 23/2)
        - Gray Whale Lawsuit, Jack Metcalf et al., vs. William Daley, et al., and the Makah Indian Tribe, 1998 (Box-folder 23/3)
        - Gray Whale Lawsuit Appeal, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 23/4)
        - International Dolphin Conservation Program Act, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 23/5)
        - International/Endangered Animal Protection, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 23/6)
        - International Whaling Commission (IWC) issues, 1997 (Box-folder 23/7)
        - International Whaling Commission Resolution (HR 425), 1998 (Box-folder 23/8)
        - Land-For-Whales Bill, 1999 (Box-folder 23/9)
        - Makah Police Chief, Lionel Adunko, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 23/10)
        - Makah Whaling Rights
          - Coast Guard Regulated Navigation Area, 1998 (Box-folder 23/11)
          - Correspondence opposing U.S. Government support of the Gray Whale Hunt, 1997 (Box-folder 23/12 - 23/13)
          - “Environmental Assessment of Makah Tribe’s Harvest", 1997 August 22 (Box-folder 23/14)
          - International Whaling Commission (IWC) member responses, 1997 (Box-folder 23/15)
          - Memos, Correspondence (outgoing), and Press Releases, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 23/16)
          - Petitions from members of Congress to the IWC, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 23/17)
          - Puyallup Tribe Involvement, 1999 (Box-folder 23/18)
          - Research on implications and repercussions, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 23/19 - 23/20)
          - Reports, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 23/21)
        - Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 / Daily Summary of Marine Mammal Issues, 1995 October 6 (Box-folder 23/22)
        - Marine Ecosystem and Coastal Management, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 23/23)
        - Marine Mammal Stranding Network, 2000 May (Box-folder 23/24)
        - Orca “Lolita”, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 23/25)
        - Other Marine Mammals, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 23/26)
    - Correspondence Files, 1995-2000
      Records from Metcalf’s D.C. Office include correspondence files documenting Metcalf’s bipartisan activities in Congress, and the range of legislative issues in which he was involved. The vast majority of correspondence is outgoing. Correspondents include the President and officials within the Clinton Administration, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, heads of House Committees, and key figures in the private/non-government sector. “Individual Letters” comprise letters composed and signed by Metcalf alone, while “Delegation Letters” and “Official Letters – Signed On” comprise letters signed by Metcalf in coalition with other legislators.
      - Delegation Letters, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 24/1)
      - Delegation Letters, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 24/2 - 24/3)
      - Individual Letters, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 24/4)
      - Individual Letters, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 24/5)
      - Official Letters “Signed-On”, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 24/6 - 24/7)
      - Official Letters Signed-On, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 24/8 - 24/9)
      - Official Letters Signed-On, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 24/10 - 24/11)
      - Official Letters Signed-On, 2000 (Box-folder 24/12 - 24/13)
      - Read File- VIPs and Officials, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 24/14 - 24/15)
    - Press and Publicity, 1995-2000
      Press and Publicity files include biographical information, photographs, press releases, and materials outlining Metcalf’s legislative activities and voting record. Press releases include statements and clippings pertaining to specific issues including the Makah whaling, as well as general press releases arranged chronologically.
      - Metcalf Biographical Information, circa 1995 (Box-folder 25/1)
      - Metcalf Legislative Profile, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 25/2 - 25/3)
      - Photographs, circa 1995-2000 (Box-folder 25/4 - 25/5)
      - Press Releases, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 25/6)
      - Press Releases re: Campaign Finance Reform, 1999 (Box-folder 25/7)
      - Press Releases re: Term Limits Statement/Info, 1999 (Box-folder 25/8)
      - Press Releases re: Makah Whaling, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 25/9)
      - Press reports re: Metcalf’s legislative activities, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 25/10)
      - Rankings (voting information), 1999-2000 (Box-folder 25/11)
    - Awards, 1995-1998
      - Award Certificates and Photographs, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 26/1)
      - Plaques and statuettes
        - Council for Affordable and Rural Housing Certificate of Appreciation, 1996 (Box-folder 26/2)
        - EA-6B Prowler Awareness Day, 1997 (Box-folder 26/3)
        - Vietnam Veterans of America – Legislator of the Year, 1998 (Box-folder 26/4)
        - National Coalition for Homeless Veterans Legislative Leadership Award, 1998 (Box-folder 26/5)
        - Spirit of Enterprise Award (U.S. Chamber of Congress) 104th Congress, circa 1997 (Box 27)
        - National Federal of Independent Business Award 105th Congress, circa 1998 (Box 27)
  - District Office Files, 1995-2000; Subseries 2
    Records from Metcalf’s district office in Everett, Washington comprise Legislative Issue files, arranged alphabetically by subject, and a small number of awards and certificates. Legislative issue files include research material, statements and reports documenting Metcalf’s investigation into the causes of Gulf War Illnesses, and contain a copy of his 2000 report “The Potential Role of Squalene in Gulf War Illnesses.” The subseries also contains materials regarding military issues and local military bases, Lummi Indian Nation requests for federal assistance, Swinomish leaseholds and water rights, the local fishing industry and regional transportation and environmental projects.
    - Legislative issues
      - American Association of Retired Persons- Medical Privacy and Medicare, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 28/1)
      - American Heritage Rivers, 1998 (Box-folder 28/2)
      - Anacortes Ferry, 1997 (Box-folder 28/3)
      - Arlington Air Station, 1998 (Box-folder 28/4)
      - Black Mountain Forestry Center Grant Proposal, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 28/5)
      - Blaine Moorage Project, 1997 (Box-folder 28/6)
      - Bonanza Queen Mine, 1999 (Box-folder 28/7)
      - Border Patrol Issues, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 28/8)
      - Border Complaints, 1997 (Box-folder 28/9)
      - Case Files A-Z, 1995 (Box-folder 28/10 - 28/11)
      - Clinton Policy - Multilateral Peace Operations, 1994 (Box-folder 28/12)
      - Congressional Trip to Egypt, 1999 (Box-folder 28/13)
      - Directory of Elected Officials, 1995 (Box-folder 28/14)
      - Everett Multi-Modal Transportation Center, 1996 (Box-folder 28/15)
      - Everett Office Memo Book, undated (Box-folder 28/16)
      - FEMA Disaster Relief for Fishermen, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 28/17)
      - Franked Mail Log, 1995 (Box-folder 28/18)
      - Frasier River Panel - Jack Giard Reappointment, 1997 (Box-folder 28/19)
      - French Slough Dike District Letter, 1996 (Box-folder 28/20)
      - Gulf War Syndrome
        - Metcalf Report (General Accounting Office Footnoted Documents), 1997-1998 (Box-folder 28/21)
        - Squalene Briefing Book, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 28/22)
        - Gulf War Illness Statistics, 1997; 1999 (Box-folder 28/23)
        - Metcalf Statements to Congress, 1997 (Box-folder 28/24)
        - Metcalf Amendment on Gulf War Illness (House approval), 1997 June 24 (Box-folder 28/25)
        - Metcalf Statement to Reform and Oversight Subcommittee on Human Resources, 1997 June 26 (Box-folder 28/26)
        - Metcalf Town Meetings on Gulf War Illness- Announcement, 1997 August (Box-folder 28/27)
        - National Gulf War Resource Center, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 28/28)
        - National Vietnam and Gulf War Veterans Coalition Letter, 1998 May 12 (Box-folder 28/29)
        - General Accounting Office Report to Congressman Metcalf, 1999 March (Box-folder 28/30)
        - Metcalf Request for Joint Investigation into Squalene Controversy, 1999 April (Box-folder 28/31)
        - Immunosciences Laboratory testimony re: Gulf War Syndrome, 1999 (Box-folder 28/32)
        - Metcalf Report: Potential Role of Squalene in Gulf War Illnesses, 2000 September 27 (Box-folder 28/33)
        - Metcalf report to Sub Committee on National Security, 2000 September 27 (Box-folder 28/34)
        - Metcalf report to Committee on Government Reform, 2000 October 3 (Box-folder 28/35)
        - U.S. General Accounting Office Re: Squalene Investigation, 2000 October 3 (Box-folder 28/36)
        - Press Articles, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 28/37)
      - Housing-Citizens for the Improvement of Nursing Homes (Snohomish County), 1995 (Box-folder 28/38)
      - Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigration Responsibility Act (Sect. 110), 1997-1999 (Box-folder 28/39)
      - International Mobility and Trade Corridor - Letter to Sen. Slade Gorton, 1998 (Box-folder 28/40)
      - Internal Revenue Service-Taxation Issues, 1995 (Box-folder 28/41)
      - Judson Lake/ Proposed Gravel Extraction, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 28/42)
      - Kennewick Man, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 28/43)
      - Lowell Riverfront Trail, Everett, 1995 (Box-folder 29/1)
      - Lummi Indian Nation - Department of Labor Grant (Casino Closure), 1997 (Box-folder 29/2)
      - Lummi Indian Nation - Federal Financial Assistance, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 29/3)
      - Lummi Indian Nation - New School Construction, 1998 (Box-folder 29/4)
      - Lummi Indian Nation - Sockeye Fishing Disaster, 1999 (Box-folder 29/5)
      - Makah Grey Whale Hunting, 1998 (Box-folder 29/6)
      - Marshland Dike District, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 29/7)
      - Morrison, Sid (Secretary of Transportation) correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 29/8)
      - Mukilteo Tank Farm Demolition, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 29/9)
      - National Assisted Housing Management Association “Mark to Market” Proposal, 1995 (Box-folder 29/10)
      - Nooksack River Erosion/Frasier River Valley/Davis Farm, 1997 (Box-folder 29/11)
      - Northwest Straits Marine Sanctuary, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 29/12)
      - Oak Harbor Development, 1996 (Box-folder 29/13)